Founding grandson without a father...
Son of the South is a history, drama film directed by Barry Alexander Brown.
In civil rights era Montgomery, Alabama, Klansman's grandson Bob Zellner must
choose which side of history to be on during the Movement.
Defying his family and white Southern norms, he fought against social
injustice, repression and violence to change the world around him
Bob Zellner, played by Lucas Till.
Virginia Durr, played by Julia Ormond.
Grandfather, played by Brian Dennehy.
Reverend Ralph Abernathy, played by Cedric the Entertainer.
Jim Zwerg, played by Matt William Knowles.
Joanne, played by Lex Scott Davis.
Son of the South is a 2020 American biographical historical drama
film, written and directed by Barry Alexander Brown.
Based on Bob Zellner's 2011 autobiography, The Wrong Side of Murder Creek: A White Southerner in the Freedom Movement, Lucas Till portrays Zellner, with Lex
Scott Davis, Lucy Hale, Jake Abel, Shamier Anderson, Julia Ormond, Cedric the Entertainer and Brian Dennehy appearing in supporting roles.
Spike Lee serves as an executive producer.
It had its world premiere at the American Black
Film Festival on August 26, 2020.
It was released on February 5, 2021, by Clear Horizon Entertainment and Vertical
Entertainment, receiving mixed reviews from critics, however praising Till's performance.
The film explores themes of alabama, civil rights,
based on true story, racism, klansmen.
The tone is emotional.